There's a specific confirmation that
happens in the market right before
you're going to enter the perfect trade
setup and that's the perfect entry
signal. Now, don't worry if you don't
understand what that is. I'm going to
break down everything in this video on
how to identify the perfect
confirmation, how to enter it with any
strategy, and most importantly, how to
make your $500 a day. Now, before we get
started into this video, I want to set
the record straight. [music] Having this
confirmation alone and not having a
strategy will not lead you to making
$500 a day. It's simply [music]
impossible. This confirmation that I'm
going to educate you in this video, you
need to implement into any [music]
strategy that you're using at this time.
Whether you're swing trader, a scalper,
a day trader, my students do this every
single [music] week and it works. So,
this confirmation is very powerful. Pay
attention because I'm about to break
down live examples in the markets
[music] as we speak. So, let's get
started with the video. Now, before we
dive into the markets and I share with
you these live examples, I want to give
you some context on what this entire
confirmation is built on, what the real
backbone of it is. And it simply comes
down to entering off of a confirmation,
not an anticipation. Now, I want you to
listen to that again. You enter a trade
off of a confirmation, not anticipation.
You want the market to show you its hand
first. You want the market to show you
their cards so you can make a decision
whether you want to place a bet against
those cards because you know what you
have, you know what they have, and at
that point does it make sense or not.
Why would you want to take a trade
anticipating what the market has when
you can simply just be patient and wait
for them to show you their hand, which
is basically waiting for the market to
give you that confirmation rather than
anticipating it. Let me break down
exactly what that means. So, the step
first is finding the proper
confirmation, waiting for the market to
show you its hand. So, that is going to
consist of two types of candlesticks,
either a rejection candlestick or a
engulfing candlestick. Now, I'm sure you
might have heard these types of
candlesticks in the past. This is not a
new unknown strategy or a new unknown
confirmation that I have just discovered
in the last 6 months of my trading. No,
this is something that has worked
statistically over years, but it's how
the market gives you this confirmation.
So, this right here is our perfect
example of our doji rejection
candlestick and our bullish engulfing
candlestick. For this example, this
market is headed to the upside. After
having a push to the upside, we've just
retested and as of right now we are
giving us this confirmation.
Now, if this candlestick is currently
fluctuating and moving up and down and
it is yet to be closed, that is the
market still anticipating this move. Up
until this candlestick closes right at
the end, whether it's the 1 minute, the
4 hour, the daily, the weekly, the
monthly, the yearly, as soon as that
candlestick closes, it is a
confirmation. 1 second before it closes,
it is an entire anticipation. I've seen
candlesticks in the last 5 seconds
before closing completely change
direction. Literally, the candlestick
could be like this and the last 5
seconds it somehow does this because it
is not a confirmation, the candlestick
is yet to close. So, you want to wait
for the candlestick to close in order
for you to get the confirmation. Now,
the two types of confirmation we look
for is either a rejection, a doji, or a
bullish engulfing or a bearish
engulfing, obviously if you're selling.
But, if you have both of these combined,
they would be a lot more powerful. The
more dojis that you would have, the more
powerful. If you have
several dojis like this set in place at
a support level and then you get a
bullish engulfing candlestick, even
[music] better. Sometimes you don't get
a doji candlestick and you just have
price approach this area, [music]
give you a small little body and then
you have a bullish engulfing
candlestick. This also works. It's a
confirmation because you have the
bullish engulfing candlestick. This
[music] candlestick is eating the last
candlestick. Even if it could be a
something as small as like this.
Technically, this candlestick [music]
has engulfed the last candlestick to the
left. So, we have a confirmation that
this candlestick has eaten the
candlestick to the left. [music]
If this candlestick is below, it is not
considered an engulfing candlestick. It
does not count. You need to wait for the
candlestick [music] to body candlestick
close above. Obviously, the higher the
time frame, the [music] stronger the
confirmation. So, when it comes to
entering any trades, my first
confirmation, despite the type of trade
that I'm [music] looking to take, if I
don't have either a rejection doji
candlestick or a bullish engulfing
bearish engulfing, I am not going
[music] to enter the trade. Now, there's
a big difference in between a doji
rejection candlestick, [music] which is
something like this, where it consists
of a very small body, and then a lot a
long wick, a long rejection, a long
tail, whatever you want to call it. And
then a wick fill. You also [music] have
a candlestick that could be something
like this, where this is technically
rejecting to the upside, but it can also
be seen as a wick fill. Now, this is
very powerful if you understand how to
use this correctly. So, let me [music]
break down what this actually looks like
on the lower time frames, quote unquote,
and how this can actually be useful for
the higher time frames and be considered
not a rejection, but a wick fill. So,
right now, let's say that this is the
daily time frame, for example. This
daily time frame is consisted of these
highs and lows. The 4-hour time frame,
let's say that it's moving like this,
right? Cuz we know that the 4-hour time
frame will have more structure than the
daily. It is inevitable. It's just built
up of more candlesticks.
Now, let's say this candlestick has
approached this area like this. So,
obviously, the 4-hour candlestick had to
go bearish in order for it to have this
retracement. Now, when the 4-hour
candlestick has gone bearish to have
this retracement, let me just move this
to the right over here so you guys can
get more of a clearer visual.
When this candlestick has gone bearish
to come into this area of interest,
this is where the 4-hour within the same
day, this is very important you
understand that, within the same day, it
then shifts to bullish.
And after it shifts to bullish, it
decides to have a bit of a retest.
>> [music]
>> So, this went bearish to have the
retracement
for the daily time frame.
Now, it has approached the area. Within
the same day, it went bearish, and then
it shifted to bullish. That's why this
candlestick at one point was like this.
It was all the way up because it shifted
bullish, but within that same day,
it came back down. Now, it could be seen
as a rejection if you only look at the
daily. But, if you were to
cross-reference that with the 4-hour,
you would see that the 4-hour is
actually just giving you the perfect
higher low.
>> [snorts]
>> Now, that perfect higher low is where
you can then anticipate that wick fill,
where then you will get that daily daily
bullish engulfing candlestick. So,
sometimes this candlestick rejection is
seen as a rejection when it's really
not. It's actually setting up the
perfect entry for the trade to give you
this bullish engulfing candlestick. Many
times when the candle when the wick is
to the downside like this,
>> [music]
>> it's because the 4-hour just simply went
all the way to the downside for
something like this, and then it had a
retracement to the upside right before.
So, once again, this candlestick at one
point was fully red to the downside, but
then it came back up, and it clearly
rejected it. Where it becomes very
powerful is where then the 4-hour within
the same [music] day shifts structure
bullish to the upside, and now you have
a very strong bullish candlestick
[music] that is closing with a bullish
body with a very strong rejection to the
downside. The day after that, it is
pretty much almost 70% chance [music]
that you will have a bullish push to the
upside. So, this combination of the
daily rejection or not really the daily
specifically, but this combination of
these two candlestick patterns together
has been what has led me to have many
avoided losses, many avoided liquidity
grabs or wick outs, and really enter a
trade and go straight into profit. Just
because I'm patient for this. Now, this
is the difficult part that people don't
really want to hear. You need to wait
for these candlesticks to close. Now,
let me get into the second point before
I get too ahead of myself. And let me
break down exactly how you can spot
these correctly and enter them and
optimize it in the right way. Now, for
this next step, I really want to break
down exactly where you should spot these
confirmations from. Because if I were
just to go over to this chart right
here, right off the bat, I can just spot
many different types of rejection
candlesticks, many different types of
dojis, many bullish engulfing, many
bullish engulfings, many bearish
rejection engulfings. These things are
all over the chart. So, you will find
these bullish engulfing candlesticks,
you will find these rejection
candlesticks, you will find these wick
fills, you will find this anywhere you
go in the chart. This is where people
get confused because they don't know
where to properly find it and where to
properly implement it. That's what I
want to break down right now. Because
this bullish engulfing and then this
rejection candlestick is completely
useless [music] if you just try and take
every single one that you see in the
chart. Because sometimes they're just
happening,
>> [music]
>> but they're not happening in your
direction or your favor.
So, the best way to spot these rejection
candlesticks is [music] at a supply and
demand zone, at a support and
resistance, at an order block. It's all
the same thing. Simply, [music]
support and resistance. You want to have
your bullish rejection candlestick and
then your bullish engulfing candlestick
at a support level. If it's not at a
support level, you don't enter the trade
and it is simply not applicable. If you
want to enter your trade to the
downside, you need to apply your bearish
rejection candlestick, and you need to
apply your bearish engulfing candlestick
once you're at a resistance level.
>> [music]
>> If you're not a resistance level, this
simply does not apply. It really is that
simple. So, let's say this market for
this region right here. Just kind of get
this right here.
Move a little bit over to this side. So,
let's say this market for example is
headed to the downside
like this. And right now we have just
approached this very strong resistance
level. If at this resistance level I am
getting my rejection [music]
candlestick, that's my first indication.
And if I then get my bearish engulfing,
that's my second confirmation. You can
enter off of just the rejection
confirmation, but it really comes down
to the type of strategy that you're
trading, how strong this resistance is,
what time frame are we in, how many days
are left in the week, what type of risk
to reward do I have, what other
confluences do I have? There's so many
other questions that you need to ask
yourself before you decide to just enter
off of the rejection or just off of the
engulfing. And this is many things that
>> [music]
>> I like to call them the extra extra
extra confirmations because you're just
going the extra mile to have the perfect
trade setup. Now, there's many times
where I have gone this extra mile and
I've missed out on these trading
opportunities because I'm trying to be
way too specific and find a very
specific setup. Where sometimes it goes
in my favor and I avoid a loss, but
there's also many times where I miss out
on these winning setups. And that's
totally fine because I accept that risk.
Now, if you want to understand how to
find this proper supply and demand zone
of the support and resistance, this is a
whole other topic within itself. There's
many different points on how to do it.
Want to learn how to do it, we have many
videos in this channel, so just go check
out our channel, search up support and
resistance here of interest, and we
break that down perfectly. But back to
the confirmation. Entering just off of
the doji rejection is enough as long as
you understand the type of trade that
you're taking and if you're okay with
that risk. Maybe you want to wait for an
extra confirmation and wait for this
engulfing candlestick and you might miss
out on a trade. Maybe sometimes after
this engulfing candlestick the trade
still might not be enough because you
wanted this to happen on a higher time
frame. This is where you can get as
creative as you'd like, but it really
comes down to on how well you understand
your trading, how well you understand
your strategy, and most importantly,
what you're comfortable with. Because if
you're not comfortable at the end of the
day with risking a certain amount of
money, it's okay. You simply move on to
the next trade. You just can't get
emotional with the trade if you end up
missing out on the trade, or even if you
avoided the loss, because you might feel
like the king of the hill. It's part of
the process. Just make sure you look for
only these two types of confirmations.
Not just enter any confirmation in the
middle of the chart. You want to make
sure it's happening at very key and
specific zones. Now, moving on to the
third subject, which is something that
is pretty overlooked by a lot of
traders, and that is that these
confirmations are used to go in the
trend of the trade that you're taking.
Now, listen to what I said. These
confirmations are to go with your
strategy, whatever type of strategy you
use, but they're pro-trend trade
confirmations. [music]
So, if you once again are at a
resistance level when you get these
rejections, this is to go in that
[music] trend. If you're bullish, and
you get these rejections from a support
level, it's to go with that trend. Now,
there's many people that, let's say for
example, after having this trade like
this,
they would have, for whatever reason
that the market decides to do this, a
bearish engulfing candlestick. Now,
they all they think about is a selective
memory of what they saw on one of my
YouTube videos. Then I go, "Alex said
bearish engulfing, I enter in that
direction." Now, if you have a bearish
engulfing candlestick form after a
perfect rejection candlestick and a
bullish engulfing candlestick, doesn't
mean that you just enter this new
direction into the market, because you'd
be completely disrupting this bullish
market being bullish from this higher
low and this higher high.
You enter this confirmation in the
direction that the market is having. If
you then, for whatever reason, have a
bearish engulfing candlestick after
that, you simply don't just change your
direction or change your bias overnight.
Because a lot of people what they decide
to do is okay, today I'm going to look
[snorts] for the market. I'm going to
look for reasons to buy. Or today I'm
going to wake up and look for reasons to
sell.
The direction of the market doesn't
change every day. Obviously, if you're
trading on the lower time frames, that's
very probable of happening. But if
you're trading more of an intraday and
more of a swing trade, you pretty much
have the same direction for the entire
month almost. So,
if for whatever reason you have a
bearish engulfing candlestick, you
simply don't enter the trade impulsively
in that direction. You just simply move
on to another trade setup. [music] Is
there a possibility that this trade from
here can retest and then go to the
downside? Of course. But now you would
only be entering a trade off of just a
candlestick and not a strategy. And
that's not a strategy. That's just
gambling at that point. So, you want to
make sure that you're very patient with
[music] these confirmations and don't
switch it if it just simply doesn't go
in your direction. For whatever reason
this might have needed to come back into
here to reject one more time and then
after it has the push to the upside.
This has happened many times in my
trading career and it's just part of the
process. But what I do is I stay true to
my plan and I stay true to my
confirmations. If I'm looking for buys
at a support, if I get a rejection to
the downside, I'm not going to just
change my bias overnight. And this
brings me perfectly to my next point,
which is going to be when you get these
confirmations. Now, what do you do? Now,
a lot of people what they end up doing
is they see this confirmation happen
first thing on Monday morning and they
decide to enter the trade right away.
Some people even see this in the last 3
hours before market close and they enter
the trade right away. Now, this is
extremely incorrect. You need to
understand when is the right time to
enter a trade with this confirmation.
There's specific sessions, there's
specific days that this actually is more
probable of having an impact. Right? So,
obviously, these are the main sessions
that you want to be interested in
trading. So, everything that is in the
darker color in orange is going to be
where there's the most amount of volume.
Everything that has the lighter color
has less volume. So, anything really
within this zone right here, you don't
really want to be entering a trade.
>> [music]
>> Anything within here, you don't really
want to be entering a trade. And really
anything in here,
you don't want to be entering a trade.
You don't really want to enter a trade
if you're just going to have volume for
about an hour because then after that
you're pretty much stuck for the next 9
hours with no volume, which simply just
makes no sense. So, you need to take
this into consideration of when you're
having your confirmation, does it make
sense for you to enter [music] at that
very point? Or should you wake a couple
Should you wait a couple of more hours
and then see how the market reacts after
that confirmation right before you're
about to enter session. Now, can that
either [music]
have your trade go a little bit more
into profit where you could have maybe
had a worse entry than after that. Or
maybe you save yourself some points and
then you got a better entry right before
we enter the session. This is obviously
going to be
statistically proven over [snorts] many
trades that you decide to take. [music]
So, this is what I like to do
personally. If I get my perfect
confirmation
for whatever reason, if I get it right
before Sydney session, I will not enter
that trade until right before London
session, into something like this. I
don't care if for whatever reason the
market has had a little bit of a push to
the upside, that is simply not my trade
at that very moment. I want to wait for
the market to have its hand first.
Again, I want for the market to show me
how it's going to react to that
confirmation. And if I can have it
essentially for free for
8 hours, that's fine. Now, I've had many
[music] times where I missed out on the
trade and by the time London session
comes, the trade is completely uh gone
from the direction, gone from the area
where I was interested in taking.
Totally fine. But this a lot of times
your price goes a little bit further
down to where my stop loss would have
been and one I end up avoiding the loss
completely, or I get a better entry
which I get a better risk to reward, I
get more stop loss, more breathing room,
and a bigger risk to reward by just
simply waiting for the session. Now,
that's only for the actual times. Now,
when it comes to the days that I'm
interested in entering the trade based
off of this confirmation,
it's really only going to come down to
Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday. [music]
Anything after Wednesday to me
personally, depending on the type of
trade that I'm taking,
simply won't have enough time for the
trade to get to the take profit. I have
an average of about 80 to 90 to even 100
pips at a time of a take profit. And if
you take a trade on Thursday New York
session, you really only have about
5 hours of New York, and then you have
the last London session, and the last
New [music] York session. You really
only have like about 14 15 hours of
decent volume that will go down. And
for me personally, it's not enough time
for it to get to the take profit. So,
even if I have that confirmation on
Thursday or on Friday, it's just part of
my rules that I won't [music] enter the
trade. Sometimes I break the rules
depending if my take profit is shorter,
if I have a very strong confirmation, if
there's a lot of momentum. There's a lot
of things that vary into that. But, the
rule of thumb is enter this confirmation
within the session [music]
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday. If you get
the confirmation before the session, you
simply wait. That's the black and white
rule. You need to wait for the trade to
enter the session, then you enter the
trade. You might have a worse entry,
[music] but you have a stronger
confirmation. You might get a better
entry, and might still take the loss.
You might get a better entry, and then
better risk reward, better stop loss.
The way that I look at it is that
there's no negative. If you get a later
entry,
>> [music]
>> but it's confirming that it's going in
that direction, it's better in your case
because you're actually right about the
trade. If the trade comes down a little
bit, and you still take the loss, well,
at least you still took a smaller loss
if you left the same [music] stop loss,
or you were going to take the loss
anyways if you would have taken it at
the confirmation. And if you are patient
and it comes back down a little bit and
then hits your take profit, you had a
better entry, you got better risk to
reward, better better everything. So,
[music]
regardless of the outcome, it's still
good. Doesn't matter. Worst case
scenario, you got a little bit of a
worse entry, but you're right about the
direction, so it's fine. So, this is
very important and it just simply
requires patience. And all of these
confirmations are so heavily overlooked
by traders all around the world. Doesn't
matter if you're a beginner, doesn't
matter if you're an intermediate
scalper, day trader, swing trader, you
need a strict rules when it comes to a
confirmation of entering the trade. I
can have the perfect trade setup. I can
have all of my confluences line up. I
can have everything be perfect on
Tuesday right at London session.
>> [music]
>> And if I don't have my entry
confirmation, I will not enter the
trade. It is that simple. Everything
needs to line up perfectly. Think about
it as an engine of a vehicle. If one
component of the engine is not working
properly, the car will have a misfire.
If one component of the strategy is not
working properly, you're going to have
negative results or unprofitability.
Everything needs to be extremely tight
and most importantly, work together. So,
to summarize, the entry confirmation has
to be confirmed once you have the
candlestick closure. Let the market show
you its hand first. Don't anticipate a
confirmation. We wait for it to close,
then we make our decision. Next, you
want to make sure that you have a doji
with a rejection or a bullish engulfing.
The more rejections and one strong
engulfing, obviously, the more powerful
it's going to be. Then after that,
you're going to make sure that you're
going to enter this at a strong support
and resistance, supply and demand zone,
order block, whatever you want to call
it, because you don't want to enter it
just in the middle of the chart. And
make sure
that it's actually happening in the
proper time. Because if it's not the
right time, it's not the right time to
enter the trade. And this is something
that I break down literally every single
week with my students. I give them my
top markets that I'm interested in
trading for the week. So, every single
Sunday we do something called Sunday
Swings where I break down the markets
that I am trading for that very week,
where I'm looking to have the specific
entry, where is the specific area that
I'm looking to enter, and the specific
day where I believe it's going to
happen. And we have a community where
every single day we're updating the
trades we're looking at, other members
are engaging back and forth, and we
break down our specific trades that
we're looking to trade every single
week. And most importantly, I review
your trades to see what mistakes you're
making. So, if you want to know more
about it, click the link down in the
description down below so you can know
more about the Swing Trading Lab
community and how we're doing things
like this
every single week. I hope you guys found
this video useful. Want to check out any
of our other videos when it comes to
strategy, when it comes to support and
resistance, trend, whatever the case is,
this channel is full of videos. So, make
sure you guys go and check it out. Hit
that like and subscribe button. And with
that being said, ladies and gentlemen,
hope you guys enjoyed this video, and
I'll see you guys in the next one.